Shad, John S. R. John S. R. Shad papers, 1972-1989 (inclusive): A Finding Aid
John S. R. Shad papers, 1972-1989 (inclusive)
- III. Briefing materials, 1972-1989
  - Background material relating to Exchange Off-Board Trading Rules
    - Appendix D: Statistical studies and data. (Box Box 9, f. 15)
    - Appendix E: Securities Exchange Act Release No. 11628, September 2, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 16)
    - Comment letter, Professor James H. Lorie, September 24, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 17)
    - Comment letter, Institutional Advisory Committee on Trading of the New York Stock Exchange, Inc., October 2, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 18)
    - Staff Exhibit One, Ad Hoc Committee on Rule 394 of the New York Stock Exchange, Inc. (Proposed Revision of Rule 394), October 8, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 19)
    - Statement of Stockholders of America, Inc.—Margaret Cox Sullivan, October 14, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 20)
    - Statement of Source Securities Corporation—Jeffrey W. Casdin, October 14, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 21)
    - Statement of the Association for the Preservation of the Auction Market, Inc.—Harry M. Jacobson, October 14, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 22)
    - Statement of Pacific Stock Exchange, Inc., October 15, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 23)
    - Statement of Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner & Smith, Inc.—Comment Letter of Donald T. Regan and Proposal for a National-Market System, October 16, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 24)
    - Statement of INA Corporation—Ralph Saul, October 16, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 25)
    - Statement of Weeden & Co.—Donald E. Weeden, October 17, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 26)
    - Statement of the National Association of Investment Clubs—Thomas E. O'Hara, October 17, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 27)
    - Statement of Morgan Stanley & Co. Inc.—Robert H. B. Baldwin, October 17, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 28)
    - Comment letter, Committee of Publicly Owned Companies, October 17, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 29)
    - Statement of Boston Stock Exchange—James C. Dowd, October 20, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 30)
    - Statement of the Securities Industry Association—H. Virgill Sherrill, October 20, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 31)
    - Statement of Ad Hoc Committee of Regional Firms—David Hunter, October 20, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 32)
    - Statement of American Stock Exchange, Inc.—Paul Kolton, (with summary). October 21, 1975 (Box Box 9, f. 33)
    - Comment letter, Professor Morris Mendelson, (undated). (Box Box 9, f. 34)
    - Statement of Gerald L. Parsky, Assistant Secretary, U. S Department of the Treasury, October 20, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 35)
    - Statement of Midwest Stock Exchange—Michael Tobin, October 21, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 9, f. 36)
    - Statements by various officials of the New York Stock Exchange, October 22, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 10, f. 1)
    - Statements by various officials of the New York Stock Exchange—Exhibits 1-4, October 22, 1975. (Box Box 10, f. 2)
    - Statement of Oppenheimer & Co., Inc.—Bernard H. Garil, October 23, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 10, f. 3)
    - Statement of New York City Economic Development Administration—Alfred Eisenpreis, October 23, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 10, f. 4)
    - Statement of Sherman, Dean Fund, Inc.—J. Walter Sherman, October 23, 1975 (with summary). (Box Box 10, f. 5)
    - Comment letter, United States Department of Justice, November 10, 1975. (Box Box 10, f. 6)
    - Miscellaneous comment letters, September-October 1975. (Box Box 10, f. 7)
    - Securities Exchange Act Release No. 11942 adopting Rule 19c-1 under the Act, December 19, 1975. (Box Box 10, f. 8)
    - Securities Exchange Act Release No. 12159 Request for Public Comment on Issues Related to the Development of a Composite Central Limit Order Repository, March 2, 1976. (Box Box 10, f. 9)
    - Letter from the Midwest Stock Exchange, “Preliminary Staff Outline of Possible Steps to a Composite Book”, November 26, 1975. (Box Box 10, f. 10)
    - Comment letter, Bunker Ramo Information Systems Division, May 25, 1976. (Box Box 10, f. 11)
    - Comment letter submitted by Junius Peak, Morris Mendelson and R. T. Williams, Jr., April 30, 1976. (Box Box 10, f. 12)
    - Comment letter, National Market Advisory Board, January 28, 1977. (Box Box 10, f. 13)
    - Comment letter, Securities Industry Automation Corporation, March 5, 1976. (Box Box 10, f. 14)
    - Comment letter, GTE Information Systems Inc., April 30, 1976. (Box Box 10, f. 15)
    - Comment letter, National Market System Committee, Securities Industry Association, June 1976. (Box Box 10, f. 16)
    - Comment letter, United States Department of Justice, June 14, 1976. (Box Box 10, f. 17)
    - Policy Statement on the Objectives, Development and Governance of a National Market System, submitted by the Midwest Stock Exchange, Inc., July 15, 1976. (Box Box 10, f. 18)
    - A National Market System: A report by the National Market System Committee, the New York Stock Exchange, July 1, 1976. (Box Box 10, f. 19)
    - Report on the National Market System, Philadelphia Stock Exchange, July 28, 1976. (Box Box 10, f. 20)
    - Comment letter, American Society of Corporate Secretaries, Inc., July 29, 1976, and A Proposal for a National Securities Market System and its Governance, Professors Sametz and Bloch, (commissioned by ASCS), June 7, 1976. (Box Box 10, f. 21)
    - Securities Industry Study, Report of the Sub-committee on Commerce and Finance of the House Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce 92d Cong., 1st and 2d Sess. (1972) (excerpts relating to the Need for Central Market System). (Box Box 10, f. 22)
    - Securities Industry Study, Report of the Sub-committee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs, S. Doc. No. 93-13, 93d Cong., 1st Sess. (1973) (excerpts relating to the Structure of the Securities Markets and the Development of a Central Market System). (Box Box 10, f. 23)
    - Comment letter, Congressman John E. Moss, in response to the Ch. 11A©)(4) Report, September 5, 1975. (Box Box 10, f. 24)
  - National Market System—Background materials
    - Securities and Exchange Commission Advisory Committee on the Implementation of a Central Market System: Summary Report,July 17, 1975. (Box Box 11, f. 1)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission Advisory Committee on the Implementation of a Central Market System: Supplementary Report, September 12, 1975. (Box Box 11, f. 2)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 11131 (December 11, 1974), Securities and Exchange Commission Advisory Committee on the Implementation of a Central Market System—Preliminary Statement of Characteristics and Principles of the Central Market System. (Box Box 11, f. 3)
    - Securities Exchange Act of 1934—Section 11A: National Market System for Securities: Securities Information Processors. (Box Box 11, f. 4)
    - National Market Advisory Board—Report to the Congress: The Possible Need for Modifications of the Scheme of Self-Regulation in the Securities Industry so as to Adapt it to a National Market System (Pursuant to Section 11A(d)(3)(B) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934), December 31, 1976. (Box Box 11, f. 5)
  - Consolidated Transaction Reporting System
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 9530 (March 8, 1972) proposing Rule 17a-15 for comment. (Box Box 11, f. 6)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 9731 (August 14, 1972) republishing Rule 17a-15 for comment. (Box Box 11, f. 7)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 9850 (November 8, 1972) formally adopting Rule 17a-15. (Box Box 11, f. 8)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No.10026 (March 5,1973) detailing the joint plan to develop a consolidated transaction reporting system filed by the New York Stock Exchange, American Stock Exchange, Midwest Stock Exchange, Pacific Stock Exchanges, and the National Association of Securities Dealers pursuant to Rule 17a-15. (Box Box 11, f. 9)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 10218 (June 13, 1973) making public the text of a letter commenting on certain aspects of the joint industry plan filed with the Commission pursuant to Rule 17a-15 and inviting sponsors of the joint plan and others to comment on the letter. (Box Box 11, f. 10)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 10671 (March 8, 1974) notifying the sponsors of the joint industry plan of the Commission’s final comments on the plan and asking that the plan be refiled. (Box Box 11, f. 11)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 10787 (May 10, 1974) declaring effective the refiled joint industry plan filed with the Commission pursuant to Rule 17a-15 (filed on April 22, 1974). (Box Box 11, f. 12)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 12138 (February 25, 1976) specifying April 30, 1976 as the date for full implementation of the joint industry plan. (Box Box 11, f. 13)
  - Composite Quotation System
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 9529 (March 8, 1972) proposing Rule 17a-14 for comment. (Box Box 11, f. 14)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 10969 (August 14, 1974) reproposing Rule 17a-14 for comment. (Box Box 11, f. 15)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 11288 (March 11, 1975) which announced that the Commission had sent letters to all national securities exchanges formally requesting that such exchanges eliminate all rules or practices which restrict access to or use of quotation information as may be disseminated by such exchanges. (Box Box 11, f. 16)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 11406 (May 7, 1975) which announced that the Commission had received responses from all national securities exchanges and that all such exchanges had complied with requests made by the Commission relating to the dissemination of quotation information. (Box Box 11, f. 17)
    - Memorandum re: Broker’s Duty of Best Execution, Andrew M. Klein and Bart Friedman to the Advisory Committee on Implementation of a Central National Market System, February 28, 1975. (Box Box 11, f. 18)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No.12670 (July 29, 1976) proposing Rule 11 (A)©) 11 which would require national securities exchanges to collect from their specialists and national securities associations to collect from third market makers, quotations in eligible securities for dissemination by such self-regulatory organizations to quotation vendors. (Box Box 11, f. 19)
  - Off-Board Trading Rules
    - Off-Board Trading Rules Section 11A(c)(4)(A) of the Securities Exchange Act. (Box Box 11, f. 20)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 11628 (September 2, 1975) noticing a rulemaking proceeding to consider amendment or abrogation of exchange off-board trading rules. (Box Box 11, f. 21)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 11942 (December 19, 1975) adopting Rule 19c-1 under the Act. (Box Box 11, f. 22)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 12159 (March 2, 1976) soliciting Public Comment on Issues related to the Development of a Composite Central Limit Order Repository. (Box Box 11, f. 23)
    - Comment letter re: In-House Agency Cross Transactions in Listed Securities by Exchange Members, National Market Advisory Board, September 24, 1976. (Box Box 11, f. 24)
    - Comment letter re: Establishment of a Composite Limit Order Book, National Market Advisory Board, January 28, 1977. (Box Box 11, f. 25)
  - Commission Rates, Membership and Member Trading
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 9950 (January 16, 1973) adopting Rule 19b-2, pp. 1-50. (Box Box 11, f. 26)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 9950 (January 16, 1973) adopting Rule 19b-2, pp. 51-100. (Box Box 11, f. 27)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 9950 (January 16, 1973) adopting Rule 19b-2, pp. 101-150. (Box Box 11, f. 28)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 9950 (January 16, 1973) adopting Rule 19b-2, pp.151-195. (Box Box 11, f. 29)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 11203 (January 23, 1975) adopting Rule 19b-3 under the Act, which prohibited exchanges from fixing the rates of commission that their members could charge. (Box Box 11, f. 30)
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 13388 (March 18, 1977) proposing certain rules under Section 11(a) relating to securities transactions by members of national securities exchanges. (Box Box 11, f. 31)
  - Additional Staff Material
    - Briefing paper: National Market System, by Bart Friedman, April 27, 1977. (Box Box 11, f. 32)
    - Briefing paper: A Composite Limit Order Book: A Current Perspective, by Lee A. Pickard, October 14, 1976. (Box Box 11, f. 33)
    - Briefing paper: Composite Book: A Solution to the Problem of Facilitating Development of a National Market System; by Andrew M. Klein, dated October 14, 1976. (Box Box 11, f. 34)
  - Congressional Hearings—Section 31(b) of the Securities Acts Amendments of 1975: Briefing Book 1
    - Securities Exchange Act—Release No. 12157 (March 2, 1976) concerning rules of national securities exchanges relating to membership and association with members. (Box Box 12, f. 1)
    - American Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: Release No. 12157, March-April 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 2)
    - Boston Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: Release No. 12157, March-April 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 3)
    - Chicago Board Options Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: Release No. 12157, March-May 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 4)
    - Cincinnati Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: Release No. 12157, March-April 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 5)
    - Detroit Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: Release No. 12157, March-April 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 6)
    - Intermountain Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: Release No. 12157, March-April 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 7)
    - Midwest Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: Release No. 12157, March-August 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 8)
    - New York Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: Release No. 12157, March-July 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 9)
    - Pacific Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: Release No. 12157, March-April 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 10)
    - PBW Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: Release No. 12157, March-April 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 11)
    - Spokane Stock Exchange: Correspondence from SEC re: Release No. 12157, March 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 12)
  - Congressional Hearings—Section 31(b) of the Securities Acts Amendments of 1975: Briefing Book 2
    - Securities and Exchange Commission—Release No. 34-13027 (December 1, 1976) concerning Section 31(b) and the rules of self-regulatory organizations. (Box Box 12, f. 13)
    - American Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: rules inconsistent with Section 31(b), December 1976-February 1977. (Box Box 12, f. 14)
    - Boston Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: rules inconsistent with Section 31(b), December 1976-January 1977. (Box Box 12, f. 15)
    - Chicago Board Options Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: rules inconsistent with Section 31(b), December 1976-February 1977. (Box Box 12, f. 16)
    - Cincinnati Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: rules inconsistent with Section 31(b), October-December 1976. (Box Box 12, f. 17)
    - Intermountain Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: rules inconsistent with Section 31(b), December 1976-January 1977. (Box Box 12, f. 18)
    - Midwest Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: rules inconsistent with Section 31(b), December 1976-February 1977. (Box Box 12, f. 19)
    - National Association of Securities Dealers: Correspondence with SEC re: rules inconsistent with Section 31(b), December 1976-February 1977. (Box Box 12, f. 20)
    - New York Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: rules inconsistent with Section 31(b), December 1976-February 1977. (Box Box 12, f. 21)
    - Pacific Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: rules inconsistent with Section 31(b), December 1976-February 1977. (Box Box 12, f. 22)
    - Philadelphia Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: rules inconsistent with Section 31(b), December 1976-February 1977. (Box Box 12, f. 23)
    - Spokane Stock Exchange: Correspondence with SEC re: rules inconsistent with Section 31(b), December 1976-February 1977. (Box Box 12, f. 24)
  - Drexel Burnham Lambert—Visit to Singapore, October 1989: Briefing book
    - Drexel Burnham Lambert—Visit to Singapore, October 1989: Briefing book Overview and schedule, October 16-19, 1989. (Box Box 12, f. 25)
    - Luncheon meeting with commodities customers, October 17, 1989. (Box Box 12, f. 26)
    - Meeting with J. Y. M. Pillay, Monetary Authority of Singapore, October 17, 1989. (Box Box 12, f. 27)
    - Meeting with Howe Yoon Chong, DBS Bank, October 17, 1989. (Box Box 12, f. 28)
    - Cocktail reception hosted by Drexel Burnham Lambert, October 17, 1989. (Box Box 12, f. 29)
    - American Business Council breakfast, October 18, 1989. (Box Box 12, f. 30)
    - Meeting with Brigadier General Lee Hsien Loong, Minister of Trade & Industry, October 18, 1989. (Box Box 12, f. 31)
    - Press conference, October 18, 1989. (Box Box 12, f. 32)
    - Luncheon meeting with corporate customers, October 18, 1989. (Box Box 12, f. 33)
    - Meeting with George E. K. Teo, J. M. Sasson & Co., October 18, 1989. (Box Box 12, f. 34)
    - Meeting with Oei Hong Leong, United Industrial Corporation, Ltd., October 18, 1989. (Box Box 12, f. 35)
Additional catalog entries
The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic databases. THIS IS NOT AN INDEX.
Subjects
Shad, John S. R., 1923-1994; United States. Securities and Exchange Commission.; Drexel Burnham Lambert Incorporated.; E. F. Hutton & Company.; New York Stock Exchange.; Tender offers (Securities).; Consolidation and merger of corporations.; Consolidation and merger of corporations -- Law and legislation.; Corporations -- Investor relations.; Deregulation.; Financial services industry.; Insider trading in securities.; Insider trading in securities -- Law and legislation.; Investment bankers.; Over-the-counter markets -- Law and legislation.; Securities.; Stock exchanges -- Law and legislation.; Trade regulation.; Speeches.